All right so here we are build stay one of gavin
...rockwell and we both work on the team in windows that's working on all join
and working with the all seen alliance work
sided today to talk to-you about the work that we've been doing with the all seen alliance in
with our partners just a brief note at the end you're going to have an opportunity to send
...your feedback I'll put the secure code up again at the and we would really
appreciate...if you take the time to submit and evaluation and give us your feedback.
So, about five years ago I set out on a mission a mission that I thought would
be fairly straightforward I wanted to build home entertainment system.
That would use a single remote.
That would be cost-effective
didn't want to spend as much on a remote control as I would on an xbox.
It would also be easy to setup easy to maintain...
easy-to-use and being the obsessive person that I am I set out
into a binge of analysis paralysis I...just about every
component on the market and in the end I got close to my goal
...xbox three sixty remote control I used to surround sound system and
a tv from panasonic that both used
...the error link to communicate with each other and life overall was good I couldn't our down the
surround sound system and I did have to switch inputs on the remote control and
...gavin I'm not nearly as obsessive as you are ignores proposal but I looked into this same as you
about the same time but I quickly backed away from it just seemed.
It's complicated it's expensive...jumbled up...the technology
generally seem to be there it seems like a little bit of ways of opportunity well I also
have kind of devolved into the basket of remote scenario I decided I
was going to try and amazon fire tv which of course uses bluetooth and
then I've got everything else on infrared and in frustration I
thought to myself how could it be twenty fifteen, you know,
this day and age when we put a man on the moon with connected the whole world with
the internet we're just on the verge of being able to three-d print replacement
body parts it still takes me three remote controls to watch tv.
Now there's just so much potential all the scenarios of interoperability and all these
devices working together at this area is just exploding.
...so many new devices being created each day
the opportunity is definitely profound the id...
is predicting in the next five years we're going to have...billion
connected devices that's for connected devices for every man woman and child on the
face of the earth but where there's huge opportunities
there's also huge challenges this example here is just, you know,
the end result of some of those challenges what we're here today to
talk about is all scene and all join this is a technology
that was created to address some of these huge challenges
and to help remove some of these huge barriers
being developers we want to give you guys and you all.
A sort of all join one-on-one so that you can understand what all join is what the
different platform components are how they work and then how you can actually bring them
into windows so we've spent some time in the past year bringing all join into windows one
at explore some of the reasons why we did this some of the benefits of this gives us as well
as get you guys...you can go out and make the next great internet of things
app will tell you how to get involved with the alston
alliance move forward potentially contribute you could back and helped drive the future of io t?
So,...in general we're going to talk about quick question
who here has heard of the all seen alliance and knows with all sequences while.
...impressive so also alliances basically the organization,
organization that is a consortium of
hundreds of companies that have come together to help
evolve the future of the internet of things it's run by the linux foundation
uses some of the people on the resources and the structure from the linux foundation but really all
seen alliance is the organization all join is the result of
the collaboration between these companies it's actually the code base and the source?
Is open-source and crops platform any developer can use
it to enabled their apps and the devices to be internet connected?
So, the example that I gave of my home entertainment system was really
just a small view into a much larger problem domain the
problem domain of the smart connected
home the technology to connect these different vices has already existed
for many years but a lot of them are trapped withinconcrete verticals in their
...it's either within and I or
...os within the manufactures schema.
But, they're all...down-and-out hard to act.
And, viewing this from app developers perspective there's really a lot of surface area, you know,
you've got different protocols different api...
a lot of different scenarios to provide support for your application
...and it's a moving target you never know when another...release
new protocol another way to integrate that sort of thing and in order for these
scenarios to become mainstream these problems half to get addressed we've got
to make it easier for app developers to provide
ubiquitous support for this new internet of things
of this whole world of devices that's going to proliferate.
In all join actually it was created without...mind all drawing
provides the necessary means for devices to
exposes standard interfaces it provides applications
standardize means for being able to discover connects
to control these devices so...join supports the platforms that all
it operates on it's on the most popular consumer resources it's on all of the most
popular manufacture os is for making imbedded devices it doesn't matter where you write your
...can be ios android or windows and it doesn't matter what system it's
return on rather...to for small devices or it's imbedded...all these can
interop...open it's the promise that we're trying to create.
...removing these platform specific obstacles
as a great but I think one of the most valuable things about all
seen in all join is the set of standardized interfaces that are
defined within various working groups the fact you can
define your own device interfaces it provides a devices with
a common language to express the functionality that the implement
and provides applications a standardized way
to discover different classes of devices and to interact with an as well
and this example let's say you wanted to build a smart connected
smoke detector this smoke detector would just sit around and wait for...
to be detected it's going to raise a notification basically
your houses on fire.
And, it might have a feedback mechanism this smoke detector might also,
you know, provide interface if you're cooking in the kitchen you have some smoke maybe want to provide a
temporary silence for that alarm right so this is a great example
internet
...device that all join would be furthered for because this was able to expose the device
metadata it's able to have on board white-white you can update the...you
can send notifications and...itself to be controlled by some type of consumer...
So, using the smoke detectors and example, you know, it's just a part of a really broad.
Spectrum of hardware that makes up the internet of things everything
from really low-power battery-powered resource constrain microcontroller
sensors all the way up to servers in a datacenter and the
all join platform was implemented with this broad spectrum of io
t hardware in mind so going back to the smoke detector example where
there's a couple different ways that we can implement the device itself we could
implemented as sort of an...which could be,
you know, hardware battery-powered microcontroller
base platform or it could be a little bit more
...the smoke detector could not
...subtype functionality were other edge devices could connect to it and that kind
of right and for resource constraint devices the all...alliance offers the
thin...of all...this is really good for micro...has a very small
who'd size and has a...language that can work on anything that supports
ongoing which is almost anything you more robust devices your hubs or you consumer apps we
have the standard for this is based on cplus-plus it also has a see offering for
...and...has a specific offerings then on top of that you have you...you
why in logic embedded into device or the controller app?
And, you can go from there so you'll see there's a little uw p box will
...back to that later the universal windows platform part of this is really cool.
So, that's the that's the core functionality that's about connecting it's about advertising
its about discovering it's about controlling kind of all
doing basics but on top of that all doing provides a set of what are called
common service frameworks these common service frameworks implement a lot of the code
that a lot of I each fees would typically right for their devices
or isv would typically have to write for their apps.
Common device interaction functionality
...talked about our smoke detector and how it's likely to want to
expose device metadata it's likely to want to advertise which interfaces
...functionality implements
all join provides the about interface for this functionality
...interface is actually integrated into the all join
corbett were including here because it offers functionality
that's on top of core the notification framework could be used by
...smoke detector to send pre packaged notifications
that are easy to...from a device or easy to consume from
...from another device which will actually show you just a minute
the notification framework also gives you the ability to provide
prepackaged data and there's even different severity levels so you can send
...information notification you...warning notification
...emergency notifications which I hope the smoke detector would...because,
you know, it's kind of important your house is burning...
All these common service frameworks are extensions upon the standard for in order to solve
...scenarios variety devices on boarding getting
a device on to your home network is one of...we have a standard way through the...
aligns and through all going to do this with...service framework so the smoke
detector that we had it had this device it doesn't have...capability but
...ip connected...be able to the...as a soft...you can connect to it
...credentials and I can get on to your network similar we have...configuration if you
want factory reset your device if you want to change its name push for
more updates this is all available to you in a common way for every device
...the configuration service framework so all of this code all join
in general abstracts the platforms specifics of the code that you're going to need to
...the core takes care of discovery and for.
Advertisement in for interactions and then these
common service frameworks layer on functionality on top of that the net of it all is that you
can focus on the functionality that specific to your app or specific
to your device and not have to write it all from scratch which is great.
...roles.
I have a little bit of new science background searcher most of you do and role more
less familiar with client-server...join use
...similar nomenclature but we use consumer and producer consumers are essentially
...clients and producers or your...
...connect sewer producer which is running a service and,
this is generally your device so in the case of some of these things on here we have lamps that are
running a service...this is actually running dividing service framework introduced by the
austin alliance to make the smart connected lighting home a little bit easier to work with.
Lamps right here are producers and the...would normally use to control it is a producer
...consumer.
It can get a little bit more complicated with the apps
being consumers and producers or something like providing service.
...controller service you have the...
Part but the lighting service
...the lighting controller service this implements different functionality and
logics such as groups and precepts and transitioning of a
...that you can use with your lights and bundles that in a logic that you can implement in your at
so you can either have...lighting app that speaks directly to the...serviceable you could have a lighting
...speaks directly to the lighting controller service and this is a way that
and app could be both consumer and producer so I'm sure that's all clears
mud so far but the basics are and devices typically going to
be a producer and app is typically going to be a consumer and either one can be
...growth...so when we set out to build all
during support natively into windows ten we had three
primary goals the first goal was to optimize security performance
to critical aspects of any coyote implementation we also
wanted to provide the most seamless and best possible
and user experience and finally we wanted to give
...rich set of tools and integration so they could have the best possible
workflow and bring their solutions to market
and the shortest period of time possible right I'm happy to say that we've metal
...scholes with bringing all...into windows ten we've managed to reduce the code
...increased security you have libraries within windows that you can link again
...they don't have to loca size of your we've provided the
...service in-box that allows communication between all...all join devices
have any windows hen device on your network you've...communication we
have invested in bringing the see api...that one red cross platform
we've invested in your bp language bindings so that you can write in the code of your choice
spit csharp javascript cplus-plus whatever you really are comfortable with.
We're making
up integration with visual studio so that.
The time that you get your idea to you define your device to
...writer app is seamless and quick.
...lots of samples go out check the microsoft get hub
have samples up there right now that show you how to set up your basic producer
...your basic consumer we have more coming
...investing heavily in the also...alliance also has several samples available.
Right well that all sounds good but I think we get which actually see some of this and actually I agree
okay so one of the great things about being a part of the all seen alliance is the
partners that we get to work with and we have here today a couple of the partners that
have been really great innovators in their individual technology areas
and been great partners in the work that we've done...windows ten
so the first partner that I want to introduce...bring onstage
is a pioneer in the smart home industry and
...implementers of extremely robust connectivity technology
and they have the largest portfolio of smart home io
to devices that are available globally are also very active members of the
...it's my pleasure to welcome joe dataceo ovens dion.
Thanks guys ...
we're really excited to be here this is really I what feels like the launch of the
fulfillment of a vision that we started twenty years ago we've been investing heavily
in building out as you just heard the largest ecosystem a products we offer over two hundred different
products connected products and the technology that wirelessly connects them
what's exciting that we're hearing about and talking about this morning is industry
titans like microsoft helping assaults bring unity
...between these devices so we're very excited and,
this morning we're delighted to announce.
An instant jan all join enabled version of our
...pro so for the first-time here in the last five minutes
our page just one lives in order these online and during
build there will be a discount offered to all developers to purchase the product.
The in all join enabled hub runs the
thin client version of the altering api.
It makes use of the speed and connectivity of your
...network while you're at your home and...cloud when you're way for
alerts andmodifications it is pretty easy to develop against the all
join api I can tell you that versus the other platforms I think that the also alliances
that a great job of doing a lot of the heavy lifting keeping that off of us
developers and, making it very practical to go from zero to fifty.
In fact in we aren't just waiting for other developers
to develop against sub pro we're eating our own cooking and also developing our own
app and with little
...from my friends hopefully we can turn a fan on and off using some of
the inbox tools that come in windows ten so.
What...what we've got here is an on
...plug-in off module basically takes a dumb fan and makes it
...connectivity to it so we can see the status of the
devices as well as control them from the interface?
And, we will be taking these tools and embedding it into
our windows application of the with a
couple a months here and we're committing today to be
...support for all ten when windows
...chips and, just a couple months.
Question.
I'm looking at somebody else's nodes here is a her.
We're really excited about where this is going we're going to play a very active role in the all
seen alliance andlead and continue to lead the future and
really connect all this all these devices the promise of the internet of things
is a great one but the challenges are real but,...we feel confident that
they also alliance...the all...really helpful in moving this forward thank you very much
So, the next partner that I want to introduce has been doing some amazing
work advanced the advancing smart connected lighting technology
and were on kick-start initially and at the time of their funding they were
the highest funded kick-start or project of all-time they also have the
only wi-fi connected multi-color eligible on market today.
It's my pleasure to introduce and welcome john
cameron vp of product from like this.
I'm on thrilled to be here I can't wait to show you guys some...you can do will join so
...we make these full color super...into any standard
...socket and, apart from bring the brushes smart bulbs on the market people of
...because they don't need any other hardware...wi-fi
stride why connect to wi-fi without another hub or anything like that as device mike is really,
really strongly in an open internet of things because we know that the real
can magic of connectivity happens when
...like you guys get hold of
...standards that I can control everything that's connected anddo things amazing things that
we hadn't even imagine so wage only...alliance out early on we
helped build this...service framework which is an extension to the old join
...andit's built around specific
locking scenarios by the setting up groups changing the color of
...discovering lots that sort of thing and we've integrated deal join service into
a product offering we've recently launched within you white-white hundred...which
...very excited about cipher map one of the it's been really awesome to say masses of the
world's leading hardware and software invited stoning the alliance and having
microsoft with a ground-up support for all...coming adding windows tennyson really tops
...off as far as...made it's so easy for...developers lucky
guys to be part of the internet of things so I like to show you an...that we quickly built here?
So, I we've replicated the functionality on app
...ios devices and,
quickly manage to make a windows version now what's really
cool about this is we can do that by...stuff like...and...color
...we got all...we didn't have to do any of the complicated stuff that we've had to do
in the other apps on boating the device...wi-fi
...discover nearby devices...know exactly what it can do what those devices capabilities are
...cullen divine...display just what
I sort of things we get all of that for free here but, the best part is we get that
our across all platforms say we've got the windows phone
...that we've now got that...
This will run...on desktop.
I'm trying not to...but yet skater moi xbox and,
surface side we've got instantly being able to build this apps
...together and we can control a
...discovery...why on all of those different form factors but,
there's more we also get out-of-the-box support for all of the cool things thatpart of windows
ten...I can grab a lot here and dragnet to mine tama start many
...I've got a lifestyle that I can say the color of my...or I can...to turn it on enough but,
my favorite is we get cool...voice...control for
free say this is the first voice controlapp that we've had
...if the...of internet connectivity work will give it again.
...ten mladic slots off.
that's going at the internet...try that again because where everyone
...it's too much wifi going on here and have internet...turn...my life...lights off?
Cycle time has gone out to the web discovered what that message...and
...may doing nothing we haven't had to do any special dave of just turn that off
...cycle to show you again.
...tanner...slides...
So, again, photons she's been learning miles eecs
and she's been doing pretty well she gets
...pretty much every time the say even...often.
Say to finish up...you know, what this means to you guys the windows to
...all join ack unlocks what we think is that completely you canvas for
developers site right now you're able to discover and control
lots that people...even know that you have access to that because that if you've got windows
ten you can control they struggle...say this gives you complete control of the
...in a room so you games can amiss...with real-time control of
colors apps can set the perfect ambient mood lighting and,
like these guys showed even what goods and appliances consent stuyvesant
...teal apps all to lamps...distant...blink to let, you know,
what this diocese so, we can just imagine, you know,
I game is delight when, for example, in your...guys from daylight to
...and the room lots...all when some...creepy?
Creepy seeing comes alone ...flash...site we just can't like to
see what you guys do this it's so easy to do and,...to posse back to these
them to...braun to show you really how easy it is thanks guys awesome...done.
So, we have a couple more devices that...to show you...quick
...down here so you might be wondering why this tv's here this is actually
and in marketweb ios equips lg tv that supports all
during natively and then I'm sure like a lot of you guys like to learn by doing
...to get my hands-on with stuff so when I started working all during one of the first things that I did was I
went created this all join enabled toaster
you might be thinking there's a huge market here right but when I looked at putting this on kick-start
...found, you know, there just wasn't that big of an opportunity but it does make a
great hardware sample and we're going to show you some apps...this as well so this is a raspberry
...one I've implemented software for this both using the thin core and using
this standard core what we've
got running here is a standard core producer that implements
toaster functionality and brian has and app is going to show you right so
we've talked a lot about the interoperability of all join but we haven't really showed
...interoperability...here we're going to use...to serve...going to go and use
...these light bulbs to put a little bit of a demo together so this toaster
have some methods start using stopped hissing I consult the darkness of...
Perhaps...need to do is restart my producer here we go.
Good now if you relaunch should be good to go.
And, then we have the simulated heating element I get a toast...done and my
wife explodes go ahead and flash over here...on the ld tv not sure if you saw it but we got a
...straight out-of-the-box additional integration necessary
...now say this darkness goes to zero to ten what if I...a little
darker I can go ahead and start testing with super dart...on for a little bit.
Imagine smoke coming out now things might...you hot no, my
...get that same notification over...on dvd and now this up
...simple took me about maybe an hour to connects these different devices or join and
...goals interoperability really well.
So, we're going to...some code rate...
Not exactly a...almost...
So, I think we need to go a little bit over some of the high levels of how we brought
all join into windows ten and the tools that we have available
for-you so the very first thing you want to go out and right...apps for
...is you don't have to go to any third-party website we've brought it all in-box with
all either in the sdk or in windows ten once you've
so you just go up get the windows insider program I think we have a new build today maybe
tomorrow...you get the tools and next have to choose your
all join device you can choose a device that already exists so we have the
...we have a hub that you can order now.
You can even create your own device it's very simple all devices are
defined...based on the interfaces you can quickly...up your own you can use
are windows ten tools to generate code from it because.
That just makes it easy and then you hook up at all...and functionality your
...combine the logic and then you can build it you can deploy
anywhere as you've seen from the keynote we can go pc phone tablet xbox is
all available for you...can use are windows store to...it across the
to billion devices that...mentioned so...software level your all
...universal windows app is going to look something like this there's really two
categories of code that you're concerned with the code that you can be using and the code that you can be
writing so below the magenta box we have all the code that we're going to
...using and...foundation we have inbox and all
joins see standard core api this is the api that
provides the functionality for your device or your app to be able to
advertise interfaces that are exposed implemented and
it basically implements all the functionality that's required for connectivity
so the foundation of all join on top of that we've built
a proper universal windows platform api so it's
got all of the type mappings in implements the patterns that you're going to
be familiar with writing universal windows applications so
this means that you can either have more low-level granular control if you need it which
you probably want or you can use our native up api for this core all
join functionality to perform all of the
fundamental all join tasks and activities then you have generated code you have
generated code component for each
...devices so in my instance where I had lamps as well as a
toaster I'd have to packets of generated cplus-plus code that I would use
in my app this is app that you don't are this is code that you don't need to touch at all we've
...for-you the only time you actually need to change it is if you modify the
interfaces and definitions of your device in that case you just need to regenerate code
it's once again available for you and then you actually use this code in
...app code so use it from them
...csharp html five javascript whatever language your most comfortable and we made
it easy for you to develop basically in whatever way your most efficient.
So, the code generator...how this works a little bit so all
join defines introspection data and this is usually in the form of xml you
can get this several different ways you can get it from manufactures website you can grab
...alliance you can even get just from a producer running on
your network so all these devices their announcing
...presents and you can look at the different signals properties and methods that
they expose and that they're capable of you take this xml and you run it through
our windows ten all join code generator this will create all the encodes
files necessary for making a controller app...client or consumer
app or producer code that you...implement in making...device.
So, these are the manual
steps broken down and this is what we're actually going to walk through but when we ship
were actual and have all this integrated with visual studio so
it'll be hidden from you won't even have to go through these
manual steps but in the meantime we've actually prepared a blog post which is going to go
live in the next day so that's going to have all the code that we're going to show you
and also all of the manual steps that are required to go through this sequence here and some
the other sequences that are necessary in this pre ship...state for you to
...join integration?
So, going back to the combined...showed we had a few different bulbs and we
...a toaster each of those bulbs
and the toaster where their own producers running on the network and they communicate on the all
...this communicates through the router node that were built into windows
ten and then communicates with the app once again through the origin
...each...devices I have a watcher that sits on the
all join bus and...for a producer to...presence.
Once it does it...the session...producer and I get a consumer
object in my app but I can use to control that producer so in the case
of the to...that I had over here...had to consumers in my app...the case of
...toaster I have one toaster consumer my app great thing about windows ten is this all
...router that...showing here's built-in so the developer you don't even need to think about it
...start automatically it'll stop automatically
and it's just another way that we've been able to optimize performance.
So, all joined is an extension of the
universal windows app story and universal windows platform
story and because of that you can write your code once.
You can optimally supplied different layout example
or html for different screen sizes are different form factors and
then target these multiple devices we actually did this that will help we
had a hands-on lab or we had a lighting control
out we had the same exact code that we deployed to...max running windows
ten-ninety for devices and ran locally on the pc is really,
really easy and it's a really great benefit for
developers and once again this is all the promises that
...made earlier it's.
You want
...something that deploys evert you can have you want to write something that tailored specifically to
a device your open able to do it...actually show that process, yeah, let's do it.
...one of the things we mentioned is that you can actually get the
xml and the device datafrom the produces directly on...networks so why don't
we go ahead and make a toaster controller...doesn't.
So, we have a tool that we're going to be shipping that
allows us to listen to the different devices on the network so we go that
and there's a lot there so I'm going to exit out that I'm just going to say this so file.
again, this is some of the detail you won't even have to worry about when visual studio twenty fifteen windows
ten ships or building it into
...visualstudio twenty fifteen integration store.
So, I can go ahead and looked at my devices that I have here.
I can see that I have...my...on your...app I have.
Quite a bit of...
apps apparently I have my combine demo that we showed we have our life explodes.
We have our...tv.
...I see the toaster in there.
What you search on toast and I'm going to make sure testers actually running?
Ok.
So, let's see okay we're up and running sorry about that.
The great thing is we can basically take any of these devices that we have running on the network and
...the moment we're going to show you how you can use this get ag xml tool to
...introspection maximal for each of the interfaces here that are
shown with their corresponding object paths also...yeah,
so, here we have it that's an interesting model number that we have
...that that's actually my birthday that's funny so you can see this...
It finds the...name which is the unique name that the...has on the bus with the
port and...the object path so we can take this information and we can put into
our tool.
As arguments.
then we get the actual interface information once again we're just going to stick this into a file.
Here we get interfaces that we explicitly implement
and we also get interfaces that are in the implicitly
implemented our behalf so we have some extra stuff here so I'm going to get rid of that extra
stuff for now because we don't actually need it for what we want to do with our toaster
okay so we're using the toaster interface that's what we have here so we defined our interface
as a sample in the microsoft domain we have the methods which is
how it consumer interfaces with a producer or initiates like
...pc...like obviously we have two of those we have...thing you have a signal that
...status from the toasters done this is how a producer generally
wall initiate contact with the consumer
and then we have a property darkness which is a un that
is rewrite accessible this is stored on the producer and can be accessed by the consumer?
...darkness property zero mildly warm ten
...charred black.
May cause your house burned down so ...go ahead and run the all join code general
...input the toaster xml will put these and.
Our cogent file core and as you can see it's pretty quick.
Or files are right here everything that you need to get up and running.
So, conceptually we...this talking about the common service frameworks and how
they provide higher-level functionality the code generator essentially gives us
something analogous to a common service framework but something that we can have
is universal windows platform component use a directly from
around right so I'm going-to go ahead and make myself a toaster consumer project?
Hopefully with this app we can and the whole phenomenon of cold...because you
got to get notified right away and what if you want to cancel toasting while you're sitting on the couch
...a real-world...
...given mentioned we generally take care of this for-you with
...visual studio extension integration but in the meantime I'm going-to go ahead and
add-in all the code that we had from.
The code generation...of all in this run-time.
And, I'll just pop that in their...
steps required here for the build that you guys are going to be working with again we're going to have the blog postal
described all the manual steps and here's all the code that I showed you earlier.
So, the very first thing when you have your
...or the first thing we have to do at least until integration is we're going
to have to add the all join capability and this capability lets you.
Tell your users essentially what capabilities
layer app has its sets firewall settings it takes a lot of communication for you.
What I go ahead and adam reference?
To the to runtime that we added.
And, then let's go ahead and just try and build.
...given...code builds.
So, this is basically where we've got all of our boiler plate code taking care of and
we're ready at this point hopefully to start writing our olds running code
...that actually uses the altering functionality.
So, I'm going to good use the tool-box.
To go ahead and add some buttons that we will use to stardom
stopper toasting...engineers were not designers so please behind.
That's the...use myself a slider.
...all change the maximum...
And, then I'm going to clean this up a little bit.
Renaming are
...variables I like the code will read quite a bit cleaner.
And, again, we could use this ui right here that
...building enamel on a variety of platforms.
For our universal windows application.
If you wanted to toast control up for surfers hub
...has a different layout you can easily supply that layout and
...target accordingly.
...and create event when the value of the darkness sliders change something that
...amazingly enough starting slider changed and we go ahead and get the code
and are cs file format happens somewhere for the buttons whenever
double-click it will create a click event nice and easy for you?
So, now actually ready to begin with mentioned the
...using windows dot devices or join name space so I'm going to that
Enables us to use all join all of the all
...resources and types.
That we're going to need...in that name space that if you look at the
...runtime project contains...code generated components...see the...because
...microsoft...from our interface xml so...ahead and,
There.
Some to go ahead and declare variables.
...main page this is the method that's going to get called when our app starts up in the page
loads.
So, we know we need a...a consumer because we have one device on the network we're going to your...and
...attachment do all that low-level communication and then we have a un for darkness.
So, let's go ahead and initialize these...aberrant will
...darkness to value...off then I have a little helper classier
for starting my watcher so this watcher wall sit on the
network and it's going to look for any toasters and toaster is added
it all trigger call back methods toaster watcher added and that all allows to
join the session and then don't ever forget to start your watcher so this is really
easy to implement because it's just plus equals...tab and that gets added for-you?
...we have a device that's already advertised
in interface will find that right away if a device comes
by leader we will get this water added method called at that time.
And, I washer added code
...first things first we have to make it asynchronous because we're using asynchronous calls.
So, we have adjoining session result from when we try and join session with the toaster on the
network if that statuses okay we can go ahead and create
are consumer and we can go ahead and...the signals bill and I'm.
So, we go ahead and register for this signals one-at-a-time and this is once again really
Plus equals tab.
Think them...generators...there...
in this we can do whatever we want solet's go ahead.
And,...when we have a toast like this...actions and
that so we have a little bit of...squiggles visual studio makes it role you to get rid of those
...add the using statements and for us.
And, that's signature right there so, when we join that session the very first thing...want to do is initialize
...variables so let me go ahead and creative darkness
A thing of course.
Is love how brand centralize is code?
So, we're
going-to go ahead and take our toaster consumer and we're going to call the very
pardon method set darkness a...pass...darkness you want.
That's all it's going to take to actually do that course after type correctly.
And, then synthesis asynchronous we have to awaited.
So, that's most of the things taken care of now we just have to go ahead and implement what happened
...the darkness
...changes so we'll go ahead and take...darkness and wall...you want.
And, then once again...have to change these to asynchronous methods.
...a part of that generated code provides us a very
easy to use a up interface that pretty
much maps identically to introspection xml but,
with udp semantics
goal now we have everything there let's go ahead and run and we should.
Get ourselves some toast nice.
So, you...good and set that to I think we might have lost our toaster
...toasters acting up today.
Just kick the toaster.
gay if we get that we get artist on we can go ahead and see that
...center along with all the other notifications of...clear that
...so that it really is quite simple and not a lot of...all
...write a windows...using ongoing.
So, the code that were going to ...to from the session page for this session
will actually also include a basic implementation of a toaster producer
so would be cool would be to
write a toaster producer implementation something like what
we've shown here and again we'll have a link to that in our session page.
So, earlier ...utopian picture the world
...slide with all of the pink dots every app knows about alternatively
every device implements all join functionality natively but we all know
that's not reality there's always going to
be a composite a different protocols are different implementations different api
is the good news is microsoft has been working on...has contributed back to the
...will also alliance something called the devices system ridge this
device system bridge makes it really easy to taking non all join devices
...wave and back net devices and to
expose these devices as virtual...devices.
There's two key benefits here one is the older interoperability story if
you already adding all join support interior jpf for windows ten
you're going to be able to discover in interact with the devices that are
exposed through this dsp.
One of the other key benefits is the fact that we can
enhance security if we have devices that are inherently less secure we can add
layers of security on top of the virtual all join
devices that are exposed off the dsp so if we need credential exchange
or encrypted data traffic that makes it very easy to do that now
...richardson is going to be giving a talk here
...the very last session on friday if you want to know more about the dsp and io
t stuff I would encourage you to check out her talk.
So, as...announced...coming out with our app in their hub
...right now you have a visual...integration that will have available
soon and we have more all join samples coming we talked about the different
common service frameworks will have a sample that shows you how to...device as
well as sample or how you receive notifications then we also have existing samples that we
have that show how to create a producer and consumer how to create signals
methods and properties and how to implement security so we've had a lot of fun working on all
...getting your hands dirty with all join we want invite all you to do the same and
what you can do today is install windows ten you can build
all join enabled up devices and apps and, you know, the
code that we're going to from the session pages a great way to get started with that but we would really love to
hear your feedback because we want to know what the developer experiences
like what did you like what did you like what was missing was great whether...involve the awesome
alliance with mentioned...open anyone conjoined there's several different working groups
that you can help to...and define the future of different workspace is whether
...appliances...be winding whether if it's just a common service frameworks it's open
...contributor code back and you can help define the shape forward
especially in relation to device schemas and introspection xml for different classes
of devices absolutely with that we'd like to open up the
floor for questions we actually have a couple microphones here if anyone has questions
you-can file your way to the aisles come forward and?
We'll handle those questions now.
You implementing the data-driven api as well as the other
Can you elaborate on the question was are we implementing data-driven api as well as the other
...for you have the...subscribe api set
...go beyond just your?
Your arming events for normal
data streams up so we have everything that's available with windows ten I don't think audio
...as anything specifically around data-driven api,
yeah, it's basically the producer and consumer semantics that we talked about
and any of the interactions that we described with.
Our pc method calls being able to set
properties you can actually get notifications on those changes and then signals and
the notification framework which the toaster actually implement support for is one of those
common service frameworks that sits on top of signals essentially.
Reply dot net or something else this code here
is running imbedded linux and this is the standard core out running on
embedded linux there's alsothin core version that I also implemented but,
you can develop similar device
implementations using windows ten ot for small devices.
Activation happens automatically...
Any other questions.
John you have to know about that...fix lc m engine.
I can get that for-you afterwards reveling link to it
...point this is a great transition.
So, these are just a few the sessions that are going to be relevant.
So, the concurrently to rightnow was ...have...here
dsp one just to go back to that was seven...that...might not be able to tell from the title.
...the process reveling to yes six
...that's actually happening right now...have to view that one online.
But, our friends and microsoft up attacker giving overview of the all the
...work that we're doing which all during...part of also...the largest
...open-source software currently in windows but we're basically paving the way to bring more
am very interested about different open-source code
bases joining windows ten go look at that top happy with your.
As we mentioned at the beginning to talk...you can take a moment to give us your feedback on
the session that would be awesome and...and I will be available for just a couple minutes down here in the
front...korea of windows insider section of course...so come
around the corner and talk percent if you have more and then so, drew over there is
...partner guy please if you want to talk to him he'll be ...some meetings after...